SENIOR SOFTWARE AND SERVICES ENGINEER

Summary	Senior Software Engineer	Innovative Services Engineer	Dedicated Technical Lead
	Offering eight years of experience in designing, maintaining, and delivering advanced solutions for MongoDB, MariaDB, and custom databases.	Contributing to the success of enhancements in DevOps environments and high availability, virtual developer workspaces, with a focus on scalability and security.	Managing small to mid-sized teams of engineers through Development, Test and Integration, and product Delivery on multiple DoD contracts.
Technical	Java & Groovy	HTML5/CSS3/Javascript	NodeJS & ReactJS
	C & C++11	Git & Subversion	Linux (RHEL, CentOS, Mint)
	MongoDB	MariaDB	Gradle, Maven, Make & CMake
	GitLab	Jenkins	Docker
	Qemu KVM	Marathon + Mesos	oVirt

Experience

Lockheed Martin

Data Storage Developer

2009 - Current

Maintained a custom Java-based Data Storage Service handling Terabytes of streaming sensor data across a distributed network. Implemented design improvements in multiple iterations of software deliveries within 80% of allocated budgets, and improving read performance by 200% and write performance by 50%.

Modern Storage Solutions

2016 - Current

Implemented a new, low-latency video streaming database using Java+Jetty, MongoDB, and HDFS offering a 300% improvement over the Java-based storage service in throughput and reduction of latency in per-frame write operations. The service was also designed to operate within a Docker container for improved portability, and improved scalability by running in a distributed architecture across the system.

Data Storage Lead 2014 - Current

Lead team of five developers to deliver enhancements and bugfixes to storage solution, meeting cost and schedule on multiple deliveries under various contracts.

Services Lead 2016 - Current

Innovated new DevOps environment for a common Development and Production platform for three large-scale DoD contracts using GitLab, Jenkins, Artifactory, Gradle, and Docker. Lead team of four developers through SCRUM Agile development to create a new environment that functions to scale, and yielded an 85% reduction in build time.

Infrastructure Developer

2016 - Current

Lead team of Services, Infrastructure, and IT engineers through procurement of cluster hardware to design a RHEL oVirt cluster to improve our DevOps environment. The approved design will reduce the hardware costs by 50-75% for delivering new products, and increase the High Availability and Data Recovery strategies by immeasurable amounts.

Research and Development Engineer

2016 - Current

Implemented new data processing cluster using Spark/Hadoop/HDFS, Marathon, Mesos, KVM, Docker, and Open vSwitch, tailor made to optimize performance for large-scale virtualization of Acoustic Intelligence software platforms. Designed improvements over previous model to increase the cluster durability, interoperability, and scalability as new hardware is added.

Awards

Lockheed Martin SPOT Awards

Modernizing Legacy Code

July 2014

Improved code sharing between large contracts which drove down Development costs by migrating legacy software to a modern toolset using Git. Identified common code libraries and refactored them into shared microservices.

Product Delivery Improvements

May 2016

Improved product delivery methods by leading the effort to implement a build utility which coordinated and executed builds of over 90 Git repositories in proper sequence, and generated build and changelogs for customer review.

Education